Bradbury, M. mss. III 1950-2000 LMC 2695
Lilly Library
Bradbury, M. mss. III
1950-2000
Lilly Library
Bradbury, Malcolm, 1932-2000.
LMC 2695
129 Boxes
The Bradbury M. mss. III, 1950-2000 consists of the papers of Sir Malcolm Bradbury, 1932–2000 who was knighted in the year 2000 for his services to literature.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
The Bradbury, M. mss. III consists of scholarly, fictional, and televisual works, including manuscript drafts and typescripts that reflect Sir Malcolm Bradbury's (1932-2000) wide-ranging career as an academic, fiction writer, and cultural critic. Born in 1932, Bradbury studied English at University College, Leicester and then Queen Mary College, University of London, where he received an MA in 1955. Between the years of 1955 and 1958, Bradbury taught at the University of Manchester and at Indiana University. Alongside a series of adult-education teaching roles in subsequent years, he received his Ph.D. in American Studies from the University of Manchester in 1962.
Bradbury focused his academic career largely on the (British and American) novel. He produced literary criticism on authors such as Evelyn Waugh, E.M. Forster, and F.Scott Fitzgerald. He was also interested in novels about university life, and gained fame for producing one of his own: The History Man (1975). Bradbury wrote five other novels, including Rates of Exchange (1983) (shortlisted for the Booker prize) and Cuts (1987). He also scripted several English television shows, including Anything More Would Be Greedy (1989), The Gravy Train (1990), and its 1991 sequel. Friends and correspondents of note include David Lodge and Bradbury's former students Kazuo Ishiguro and Ian McEwan.
Arrangement
The collection is in the arrangement as received.
Scope and Content Note
The papers include both extensive material for literary and scholarly works from earlier periods of his life, as well as manuscript drafts, typescripts, televisual scripts, correspondence, and copious related material for such later works as The Atlas of Literature (London: De Agostini, 1996), Inside Trading: A Comedy in Three Acts (London: Methuen, 1997), and his final novel To the Hermitage (London: Picador, 2000). The papers also provide additional detailed insight into his life as a teacher, lecturer, and literary critic.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2002
Authors, English--Correspondence; Literary landmarks.; Fiction; Humorous stories, English; Television; Criticism; Bradbury, Malcolm, 1932-2000 --Correspondence.; University of East Anglia --Faculty --Archives.
- Content List Arrangement Note
  Arrangement
  The following is a brief listing of the contents or subject of each folder, notebook, file box or accordion file as labeled. Years indicate folders of miscellaneous papers not labeled and may include correspondence. Some materials were formerly filed in hanging folders; loose items were removed to acid–free folders.
- Daily diaries (Box 1)
- Diderot: To the Hermitage manuscript (Box 1)
- Diderot (Box 2)
- Lectures 1 and 2 (Box 2)
- Roosevelt and Churchill (special relationship) (Box 2)
- Millennium library (Box 2)
- Rates of Exchange (Box 3)
- Book reviews, (3 volumes) (Box 3)
- Book Reviews (Box 4)
- 1994–1995, (2ff.) (Box 4)
- 1996 (Box 4)
- 1996 (Box 5)
- University reports of the Vice–Chancellor (Box 5)
- Scrapbook–type papers (printed) (Box 5)
- Misc. papers, (4ff.) (Box 5)
- Misc. papers (Box 6)
- Many notebooks (Box 6)
- Diderot (Box 6)
- Radio plays (Box 6)
- 1996 (Box 7)
- 1995, (2ff.) (Box 7)
- Diderot (Box 8)
- Misc. papers (Box 8)
- Killing Kindness (Box 8)
- Talks, interviews, etc (Box 8)
- Stormy Day with Choppy Waves (Box 8)
- Fox on the Run, (2ff.) or notebooks? (Box 8)
- A Touch of Frost (Box 8)
- Keep to the Car (Box 8)
- April Shroud (Box 9)
- Touch of Frost (Box 9)
- papers, 1997; (9ff.) (Box 9)
- papers, 1996; (2ff.) (Box 9)
- letters, 1993 (Box 10)
- Farley Dickinson (Box 11)
- Hay–on–Wye Literary Festival (Box 11)
- Neil Reeves material (Box 11)
- Wheatlands Conference (Box 11)
- American Literature courses (Box 11)
- 1994–1995 (Box 11)
- 1998 (Box 11)
- Authors U.S.A. (Box 11)
- Higher degree exam (Box 11)
- unfinished novel (Box 11)
- Early Plays, (2ff.) (Box 12)
- papers, 1999; (3ff.) (Box 12)
- Rates of Exchange (Box 12)
- History Man – proofs (Box 12)
- 1999–2000 (Box 12)
- Curtis Brown papers, 1999 (Box 13)
- 1999, (5ff.) (Box 13)
- various articles by other authors (Box 13)
- Gravy Train series II (Box 13)
- Seven spiral notebooks (Box 13)
- Bloodstain on the Bushes (Box 13)
- idea for new book (Box 13)
- Furling the Flag – TV series (Box 14)
- Flush – screenplay (Box 14)
- University article with Bryan Wilson (Box 14)
- Tamara (Box 14)
- various literary articles (Box 14)
- Atlas of World Literature (Box 15)
- Dangerous Pilgrimage, 3 notebooks (Box 15)
- Dr. Criminale, 2 notebooks (Box 15)
- Unsent Letters (Box 15)
- TV and the Writer (Box 15)
- 1998 (Box 15)
- letters 2 groups, 1994–1995 (Box 16)
- "Answered Put in letter box" (Box 16)
- 1996 (Box 16)
- Recent press articles, 2 notebooks (Box 17)
- Introductions to books, 2 notebooks (Box 17)
- Brilliant creatures (Box 17)
- Suitable Vengeance, 2 notebooks (Box 17)
- Ph.D. American Expatriates in Europe and drafts (Box 18)
- Literary periodicals (Box 18)
- Spy Club (Box 18)
- Touch of Frost, 2 notebooks (Box 19)
- Vortex film screenplay (Box 19)
- Flaxborough Mysteries (Box 19)
- Dalziel and Pascoe "Waking the Dead", 2 notebooks (Box 19)
- stuff, 1992; (3ff.) (Box 19)
- Arts Policy Committee, 80's and 90's (Box 19)
- Misc. printed (Box 19)
- Misc. printed 70's–90's [arts?], (2ff.) (Box 20)
- Room With a View Penguin edition page proofs (Box 20)
- University stuff, (3ff.) (Box 20)
- Fulbright (Box 20)
- Bring Me to the Banqueting House by Biderman (Box 20)
- Maniacs (Box 20)
- Clippings (Box 21)
- Research for New York Times (Box 21)
- stuff, 1998 (Box 21)
- Five notebooks (Box 21)
- Early humor for American magazines (Box 21)
- Tamara research (Box 22)
- Touch of Frost, 2 notebooks (Box 22)
- Cold Comfort Farm – TV (Box 22)
- Kavanagh, 1st and 4th drafts (Box 22)
- Swan lectures, Italy/Greece (Box 22)
- Challenge of Language in European Films (Box 22)
- bios of various writers (Box 22)
- Millennium library (Box 22)
- Printed articles about Bradbury (Box 23)
- Printed articles about Bradbury (Box 24)
- Early critical articles, 2 notebooks (Box 24)
- Leaving the 50's (Box 24)
- Diderot at the Hermitage (Box 25)
- Two address books (Box 26)
- History Man – TV version, variant texts, etc., 3 notebooks (Box 26)
- Eleven notebooks (Box 26)
- 22 small spiral notebooks and pads (Box 27)
- Notes for Dr. Criminale (Box 27)
- 1950's personal university letters (Box 27)
- Americanization in Europe (Box 27)
- Furling the Flag––last draft and Ep. 1,2,3 (Box 27)
- In the Red 2nd draft (Box 27)
- Diderot at the Hermitage, 4 notebooks (Box 28)
- Liar's Landscape various drafts (Box 29)
- Short story ideas (Box 29)
- Early humorous articles (Box 29)
- Modern British novel (Box 29)
- In the Red (Box 30)
- Pemberton Billing and the great Black book (Box 30)
- Hong Kong file (Box 30)
- Draft Hong Kong (Box 30)
- New novel, 1991 (Box 30)
- Three spiral notebooks (one marked "Scenes from Provincial Life") (Box 30)
- Small spiral notebooks (21) (Box 30)
- Literary periodicals (Box 31)
- Hermitage writings notes (Box 31)
- stuff, 1995 (Box 31)
- stuff, 1995 (Box 32)
- History of Literature and English (Box 32)
- Humorous articles (Box 32)
- Tamara, 2 notebooks (Box 32)
- IMAX dimensions and detections (Box 32)
- Flush, 2 notebooks (Box 32)
- In the Red (Box 32)
- Dr. Criminale (Box 33)
- Modern British novel (Box 33)
- Scenes from Provincial Life (Box 33)
- The Gravy Train (Box 33)
- Inside Trading (Box 33)
- Misc. writings, (3ff.) (Box 33)
- Modern British Fiction, 2 notebooks (Box 34)
- Rates of Exchange, 1st draft (Box 34)
- Modern American Fiction (Box 34)
- Calendar diaries, 1993; 1994; 1996; 1997; 1998; 1999 (Box 35)
- Calendar/address book (Box 35)
- Publication records 2 ledgers (Box 35)
- Nine date books (Box 35)
- American Literary Expatriates in Europe (Box 35)
- 7 small notebooks (Box 35)
- 2 misc. folders (Box 35)
- To the Hermitage (Box 35)
- Literary periodicals (Box 36)
- To the Hermitage (Box 36)
- Teaching notes, (2ff.) (Box 36)
- Spiral notebooks (10) (Box 36)
- Angus Wilson (Box 37)
- Old letters from various years (Box 37)
- 1993–1995* (Box 37)
- 1993–1997* (Box 37)
- 1995–1996* (Box 37)
- 1998–1999* (Box 37)
- Wharfside – TV series (Box 37)
- Porterhouse Black (Box 37)
- Rates of Exchange – film version (Box 37)
- The Wench is Dead, 2 notebooks (Box 37)
- Letters of appointment (Box 37)
- *"important writers" (Box 37)
- A Mixture of Frailties (Box 38)
- Kavanagh (Box 38)
- Tamara, 2nd draft (Box 38)
- Spy Club: The Amorous Ambassador (Box 38)
- Dalziel and Pascoe (Box 38)
- A Touch of Frost (Box 38)
- Hard Frost (Box 38)
- Recent press articles, 2 notebooks (Box 39)
- Articles and lectures/Modern fiction (Box 39)
- Articles and books (Box 39)
- Dr. Criminale, copy 2 (Box 40)
- Kavanagh (Box 40)
- In the Red, new version (Box 40)
- 1995 (Box 40)
- metal box of file cards (Box 41)
- Academic diaries (9) (Box 41)
- Ideas book (Box 41)
- "Scribbling diaries", 1968; 1969 (Box 41)
- Ph.D. American Literary Expatriates in Europe (Box 41)
- Dr. Criminale draft (Box 41)
- Very Special Relationship, (9ff.) (Box 42)
- Porterhouse Blue (Box 42)
- Summer term, 1969 (Box 42)
- Autumn term, 1968 (Box 42)
- Spring term, 1970 (Box 42)
- Summer term, 1970 (Box 42)
- Autumn term, 1969 (Box 42)
- Spring/Summer, 1968 (Box 42)
- Autumn term, 1967 (Box 42)
- Summer, 1967 (Box 42)
- Misc. university papers (Box 42)
- Post in English lit., 1973 (Box 42)
- Post in American lit., 1971 (Box 42)
- References (Box 42)
- 2000 (Box 43)
- Post in American lit., 1973 (Box 43)
- References (Box 43)
- 2000 (Box 44)
- Flush (Box 44)
- A Suitable Vengeance (Box 44)
- Porterhouse Blue (Box 44)
- The Gravy Train, 1st series (Box 45)
- East/West Center (Box 45)
- Misc. university, (3ff.) (Box 45)
- Misc. clippings (Box 45)
- Letters, 1970; 1980; 1990; 1991 (Box 45)
- 1998 (Box 45)
- Printed and clippings, (3ff.) (Box 46)
- Four notebooks (Box 46)
- 23 university catalogs (Box 46)
- Three small notebooks (Box 46)
- Important clippings on philosophy (Box 47)
- Notions for books (Box 47)
- The Development of English Literature (Box 47)
- Rates of Exchange (Box 47)
- Dalziel and Pascoe (Box 47)
- The liberal imagination and the Post–war American novel (Box 47)
- The Posthumous reputation of Catherine the Great (Box 47)
- Crime and Spy fiction (Box 47)
- Seymour Betsky – Utrecht Institute (Box 47)
- Material on TV/Drama/Policy/ER (Box 47)
- British Association for American Studies: Correspondence (Box 47)
- Travel – useful (Box 47)
- Clippings on American expatriates (Box 47)
- Comparative literature conference UEA, Dec. 1975 (Box 47)
- Clippings (Box 47)
- UNESCO consultation, Feb. 72 (Box 47)
- Lecture/lunchtime Place of novel in modern world (Box 47)
- Eastern Arts Association (Box 47)
- Clippings on Spies and Codes (Box 47)
- US/UK Educational Association (Box 47)
- Talks on writings for TV/ER/Writing crime (Box 47)
- BAAS annual conference, UEA, 1970 (Box 47)
- various items/modernism (Box 47)
- Miscellaneous conferences (Box 47)
- Millennium library correspondence (Box 48)
- Everyman's Library – millennium scheme (Box 48)
- Best of British Authors and publicity (Box 48)
- Young British writers (Box 48)
- Interviews with Bradbury, (3ff.) (Box 48)
- UEA writers (Box 48)
- Contemporary writers (Box 48)
- Andrew Motion (Box 48)
- Articles and reviews for New York Times (Box 48)
- New language of morals/nymphet (Box 48)
- Book reviews for American magazines (Box 48)
- Penguin books mss. reissues (Box 48)
- Book review/UK (Box 48)
- Recent conferences (Box 48)
- Old articles/Lit. drafting (Box 48)
- Updike (Box 48)
- Advisor/Waterstone & Co. Guide to Books (Box 48)
- Salzberg seminar (Box 48)
- Clippings on Contemporary writers/American (Box 48)
- Book reviews (Box 48)
- Fiction in the '70s (Box 48)
- Seminar in Atlantic studies (Box 48)
- Debates/lectures/conference speeches (Box 48)
- International festival of authors at Harborfront, Oct. 1985 (Box 49)
- Scholars–in–residence, June 1987 (Box 49)
- USIS conference at UEA, Jan. 1968 (Box 49)
- Opportunities (Box 49)
- Tromsø chair (Box 49)
- Penguin history of English Literature (Box 49)
- History Man – correspondence about publicity (Box 49)
- Early editing folio/Penny Poems (Box 49)
- Later 20th Century novel (Box 49)
- New writing (2)––Edtd. For Minerva & the British Council (Box 49)
- Proposals for new books (Box 49)
- Catalogues/programmes/exhibitions (Box 49)
- Visit to Zurich (Box 49)
- Articles on Bradbury (Box 49)
- Discussions of own work (Box 49)
- Correspondence (Box 49)
- Arrow, etc./live matters (Box 49)
- Interview with Bradbury (Box 49)
- UEA/Wurzburg/Paris link (Box 49)
- Book Trust (Box 49)
- [Christmas cards, printed and other stuff, 1996–1997] (Box 49)
- Judge/ Ian St. James awards, 1992 (Box 49)
- Fifties novel (Box 49)
- The Glass Tower, novel (Box 50)
- Writer and critic, article and lecture (Box 50)
- Some early writing (Box 50)
- Nymphet (Box 50)
- Short story: A Game of Miniature Golf (Box 50)
- P.E.N. (Box 50)
- B.A.A.S. (Box 50)
- Stories – Convergence (Box 50)
- Visit to East–West Center Honolulu, Summer 1975 (Box 50)
- SDP Arts Policy Committee (Box 50)
- Porterhouse Black – possible stage play (Box 50)
- Notes for New Fiction (Box 50)
- Mike Shaw/Live Matters (Box 50)
- Contemporary Playwrights – Arthur Miller clippings (Box 50)
- Letters re: CBE (Box 50)
- EAAS conferences (Box 50)
- copies of poems (Box 50)
- Development of English literature, UEA (Box 51)
- Wharfside/new TV project/John Thaw (Box 51)
- Practical criticism: master sheets (Box 51)
- Stephen Crane DNB (Box 51)
- Chateaubriand, new novel (Box 51)
- various articles on Postwar English novel (Box 51)
- Journalism/Daily Mail (Box 51)
- Weekly Standard – USA (Box 51)
- Diderot/Chateaubriand lecture BAAS (Box 51)
- TV projects recent (Box 51)
- Essential library – Mail on Sunday (Box 51)
- Hong Kong novel (Box 51)
- National Central Library (Box 51)
- Arrow/Arona advising (Box 51)
- Special Relationship scripting (Box 51)
- Prelim. lecture: Literature and society (Box 51)
- Teaching/extra–mural – Nottingham & Hull Universities (Box 51)
- Modern tragedy – course (Box 51)
- Contemporary cultural studies seminars (Birmingham) (Box 51)
- Literature & Sociology: useful articles (Box 51)
- Research seminar, UEA (Box 51)
- Twenties course/UEA (Box 51)
- Daily Mail – journalism (Box 51)
- Courses on literary criticism/Nottingham & Birmingham (Box 51)
- BAAS publications – sub–committee (Box 52)
- Millennium project – Interactive design: Modernism and the Great War (Box 52)
- BAAS annual conferences: Hull 1974/Glasgow, 1975 (Box 52)
- Millennium project – ...:The global war (Box 52)
- Reports for publishers and magazines (Box 52)
- Press cuttings (Box 52)
- Editorial boards – various (Box 52)
- Stockholm Conference papers (Box 52)
- Interviews with Bradbury (Box 52)
- Lecture/European backgrounds of Modern American Literature (Box 52)
- Various teaching arrangements – Birmingham (Box 52)
- Course on Literature & Sociology, UEA (Box 52)
- Literature and Sociology reader (Box 52)
- Millennium library project, 1997–1999 (Box 53)
- Pudiger Ahrens, Festschrift conference, Wurzburg, 1998 (Box 53)
- British Council, 1985–1988 (Box 53)
- British Council tours visit to Slovenia, 1999 (Box 53)
- Visit to Spain – Spring, 1975 (Box 53)
- Atlas of Literature – Mapping (Box 53)
- Atlas of Literature – Contributions, letters, etc. (Box 53)
- Stepping Westward – page proofs (Box 53)
- Stepping Westward – Bet's abridged version for BBDC radio "Story Time", read by Robert Powell (Box 53)
- A Touch of Frost – Unknown soldiers (Box 54)
- A Touch of Frost – Deep Waters (Box 54)
- American Lit – The American Risorgimento, etc. (Box 54)
- American naturalism – Draft material for sphere articles & revision, 1985 (Box 54)
- Stratford–Upon–Avon series – Contemporary American Novel (Box 54)
- Columbia History of American Literature – essay on novel, 1945–1960 (Box 54)
- Misc., (2ff.) (Box 54)
- Articles/lectures 90's (Box 54)
- Lectures/printed 90's (Box 54)
- Printed/Festival brochures & programs (Box 54)
- Arts Council – Writer's Fellowships conference, 1983 (Box 54)
- Film – press kits, synopsis – various broadcasting related brochures (Box 54)
- Article on Peter Aleshkovsky (Box 55)
- Pilots workshop – Oct. 98 & misc printed (Box 55)
- British Council trous: Slovenia, 1999; Wurzburg, 1998; Wilberburg, 1988; Berlin, 1986; Spain, 1975 (Box 55)
- MA in creative writing –, 1988; 1989 (Box 55)
- MA in creative writing –, 1986; 1987 (Box 55)
- Touch of Frost/ Keys to the Car, TV (Box 56)
- Touch of Frost, shooting script, House Calls, TV (Box 56)
- Dalziel & Pascoe/An Autumn Shroud, script/shooting, etc.) TV (Box 56)
- Atlas of Literature (notebook) (Box 57)
- The Modern African Novel (dup.) orig. text (Box 57)
- TV proposal projects various years (Box 57)
- Norwich/Norfolk material (Box 57)
- Assorted letters – 2000–2001, plus occasional letters from later dates (Box 57)
- The Modern British Novel (Box 58)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – key material (Box 58)
- Contemporary American Fiction – notes, articles, etc. (Box 58)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – Research & drafts, Chateaubriand to James (Box 59)
- The Modern American Novel – photocopy (Box 59)
- The Glittering Prizes – script (Box 59)
- Porterhouse Blue – script (Box 59)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – book draft (Box 59)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – key drafts of materials (Box 59)
- Complex Fates – BAAS pamphlet? (Box 59)
- Project for book – The Outland Dart… (Box 59)
- Radio Broadland, (3ff.) (Box 59)
- The Practice of Reading: Interpreting the Novel, (2ff.) (Box 59)
- In the Red – 3 episodes BBC–II TV (Box 60)
- In the Red – BBC–TV (Box 60)
- Furling the Flag – submitted version (Box 60)
- Creative writing book – notes (Box 61)
- Standing in the Henry – TV play, drafts and script (Box 61)
- Imaginary friends (3 pts.) adapted for Thames TV, shooting script (Box 61)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – drafts of early versions (Box 61)
- Articles and reviews by MB (Box 62)
- Scenes from Provincial Life, Ep. 1, 2, 4, 6 (Box 62)
- The Green Man – Draft scripts & final scripts (Box 62)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – various plans for earlier book; UEA courses (Box 63)
- Evelyn Waugh book – early version/possible new version? (Box 63)
- [misc. writings], (2ff.) (Box 63)
- Possible book on creative writing (Box 64)
- Gravy Train series – Series 1 & 2 (Box 64)
- Grantchester Grind by Tom Sharpe (sequel to Porterhouse Blue, (2ff.) (Box 64)
- Class works – proofs & planning (Box 65)
- Early writing – notes, scraps, old letters (Box 65)
- History of American Literature – proof (Box 65)
- Saul Bellow – research material on book, etc. (Box 66)
- Atlas of Literature – design & material (Box 66)
- Introduction to books – Everyman, etc. (Box 66)
- Great Writers – Proust, Joseph Conrad (Box 66)
- Hong Kong material – research for Furling the Flag (Box 67)
- The Knights of the Spiral Stairs by Gudmundsson (photocopy) (Box 67)
- Helen Maynard thesis on Iris Murdoch (Box 67)
- Barrow, Andrew. International Gossip (proof) (Box 67)
- Crace, Jim. Arcadia, (3ff.) (Box 67)
- Cuts, A Short Novel by MB, (3ff.) (Box 67)
- Unsent letters by MB (Box 67)
- Hill, Reginald. Arms and the Women: An Eliad, (2ff.) (Box 67)
- Stories & articles for Nottingham newspapers (clippings) (Box 68)
- Grass. My Century (Box 68)
- Okri, Ben. Songs of Enchantment (Box 68)
- The journals of John Cheever, (3ff.) (Box 68)
- Doctorow, E.L. World's Fair, (3ff.) (Box 68)
- Patterson – radio comedy series with Chris Bigsby – scripts (Box 68)
- The Wheel Turns – script no. 5 for the Rothschilds (Harlech TV, 13 pt. series) (Box 69)
- Patterson – comedy radio series in 8 episodes for Radio 3 (Box 69)
- Tender is the Night scripts, BBC–TV (Box 69)
- UEA – creative writing – stories etc. for BA undergrad course (Box 70)
- UEA – MA in creative writing – stories, 1990/1991 (Box 70)
- Rates of Exchange – Why Come to Slaka? etc – background material – Eastern Europe in the Cold War (Box 70)
- Dalziel and Pascoe – Ruling Passion, shooting scripts, etc. (Box 71)
- Dalziel and Pascoe – Foreign bodies – Waking the Dead (Box 71)
- Postwar American Fiction – various lectures and talks (Box 71)
- Youth at the Helm – Insider Trading play for playhouse (Box 72)
- Dangerous Pilgrimages – drafts for book (Box 72)
- Imaginary Friends by Allison Lurie – adapted for Thames TV (Box 72)
- UEA creative writing undergrad course (Box 72)
- Rates of Exchange – variant text (Box 73)
- Rates of Exchange – photocopies of final mss. for editing (Box 73)
- Elizabeth Bradbury – No Name – novel by Wilkie Collins dramatized for BBC radio (Birmingham) (Box 73)
- Foreign conferences, 1985 thru, 1992 (Box 74)
- Millennium library – CD Rom – Anglia–Everyman (Box 74)
- Doctor Criminale – drafts of novels (Box 74)
- Drabble, Margaret. Angus Wilson – proof (Box 74)
- Papers by other writers – sent to MSB (Box 75)
- Stallybrass/Fontaine Dictionary of Modern Thought (Box 75)
- Dent Encyclopedia (Box 75)
- Cultural Studies series (Box 75)
- Fontana/Literature of Sociology series (Box 75)
- Photocopies of articles by self: Age of Parody, Putting in the Person, etc. (Box 75)
- Entries for Who's Who/Author's directories (Box 75)
- Curriculum vitae (Box 75)
- Recent CV (Box 75)
- Misc. (Box 75)
- F/Encyclopedia entries, (2ff.) (Box 75)
- Vinson – Green files/St. James Press (Box 75)
- Thomas & Hudson Encyclopedia, (2ff.) (Box 75)
- Dictionary of Criticism (Box 75)
- Faqir, Fadia. The Yarn–Spinner (Box 75)
- Misc. writings (Box 75)
- untitled work – spiral bound (Box 75)
- British Council lectures tours – 60s–90s, (3 packages) (Box 76)
- British Council – mostly printed (Box 76)
- The Mobil Story Prize – judging, Auckland, NZ (Box 76)
- Cold Comfort Farm – BBC–TV, Jan. 1995 (Box 77)
- The Gravy Train Goes East – Channel 4 TV – scripts & rewrites (Box 77)
- The Modern American Novel, (5ff.) (Box 77)
- Stepping Westward – radio version, (2 boxes) (Box 78)
- Misc. papers (Box 78)
- E.M. Forster – proofs (Box 78)
- Doctor Criminale – corrected proofs (Box 78)
- Rates of Exchange – uncorrected proofs (Box 78)
- Coe, Jonathan. What a Carve Up!, (3ff.) (Box 78)
- Unknown material – possible mss. (Box 79)
- UEA material (Box 79)
- various conference/seminar material (Box 79)
- David Lodge – clippings, program, photograph (Box 79)
- David Lodge letters (Box 79)
- David Lodge. Paradise News, (2ff.) (Box 79)
- Gravy Train – clippings; misc.; draft script of Episode 2?, revision drafts, Apr. 1989; (4 folders) (Box 79)
- EC [European Community] cuttings (Box 79)
- In the Red – radio scripts (Box 79)
- The Contemporary English Novel – various lectures & articles (Box 80)
- Literature and Sociology – drafting for unfinished book with Bryan Wilson, research notes (Box 80)
- Press articles – clippings, (2ff.) (Box 80)
- Postmodernism – articles, notes, conferences, offprints, etc. (Box 81)
- Gravy Train Goes East – drafts of scripts (Box 81)
- Recent press articles – clippings 7 magazines, (3ff.) (Box 81)
- Dalziel and Pascoe, A Killing Kindness – shooting scripts (TV) (Box 82)
- Dalziel and Pascoe – Plater scripts – Clubbable Woman (TV) (Box 82)
- Blott on the Landscape – first hand scripts (Box 82)
- Press articles – clippings (Box 82)
- Dalziel and Pascoe/Series V/ Scripts of Sweet Lazarus (Ep.1)/ Cunning Old Fox (Box 83)
- The Enigma, play for BBC TV from story by John Fowles (Box 83)
- Hong Kong material for script (Box 83)